The impossible comes true.
The Greatest Showman is a drama film directed by Michael Gracey.
The story of American showman P.T.
Barnum, founder of the circus that became the famous traveling Ringling Bros.
and Barnum & Bailey Circus.
P. T. Barnum, played by Hugh Jackman.
Phillip Carlyle, played by Zac Efron.
Charity Barnum, played by Michelle Williams.
Jenny Lind, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Anne Wheeler, played by Zendaya.
Lettie Lutz, played by Keala Settle.
The Greatest Showman is a 2017 American musical period drama film directed by Michael Gracey from
a screenplay by Jenny Bicks and Bill Condon, based on an original story by Bicks.
The film stars Hugh Jackman, Zac Efron, Michelle
Williams, Rebecca Ferguson, and Zendaya.
Featuring nine original songs written by Benj Pasek and Justin Paul, and an original musical orchestral score composed
by John Debney and Joseph Trapanese, the film is a heavily fictionalized depiction of the life of P.
Barnum, a showman and entertainer who created the Barnum &
Bailey Circus, and its star attractions.
The Greatest Showman premiered on December 8, 2017, aboard the RMS Queen Mary 2 in New York City and was released in the United States on December 20,
by 20th Century Fox, seven months after Ringling folded and six years before the circus was reinstated as an animal free institution.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances, music, visuals, and
production values, but criticised its artistic license and overdramatic story.
It was a box-office success, grossing $459 million
worldwide against a $84 million budget.
The film received nominations for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy and Best
Actor – Musical or Comedy for Jackman at the 75th Golden Globe Awards.
The Greatest Showman won the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song for "This Is Me", which was also nominated for Best Original
Song at the 90th Academy Awards, and won Best Compilation Soundtrack for Visual Media at the 61st Annual Grammy Awards.
A stage musical adaptation is in development from the Disney Theatrical Group following their parent company's
acquisition of the film and the Fox assets in 2019, which will open in Bristol in spring 2026.
The film explores themes of adultery, circus,
musical, biography, rags to riches.
The tone is emotional.